Tijesunimi Oloyede

09033364819 | tjoloyede9@gmail.com | ikeja, lagos

SUMMARY

Front-end developer with 6+ years of experience designing and building responsive web design and mobile apps in the financial industry. Proficient with CSS and JS Frameworks such React, Express js ,Node js,Mongo DB, with extensive knowledge of UX and user psychology. Notable achievements include boosting the conversion rate of an existing website by 80% with improved code and design.

TECH STACK

React

React Redux

Redux Tookit

JQuery

Git

EXPERIENCE

MVAA | ikeja, lagos

front end engineer | 02/2022 - 12/2022

- Extensive usage of JavaScript, React Js, Node Js, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Material UI, JQuery/AJAX, JSON, HTML5, CSS3.
- Developed certain features of the application functionality i.e. CRUD(Create, Read, Update, Delete) and responsive design.
- Implemented React JS for reusable components (multi-field form elements), background file uploads.
- Responsible for implementing UI mockups, integrating third part React libraries, and handling/creating Redux store data.
- Worked with Node Packet Manager, Mongo DB and used React JS library functions for the logical implementation part client side for all application.
- Implemented React JS Controllers to maintain each view data.
- Environment: Html 5, CSS 3, LESS, SASS, JavaScript, ES6, React JS, Axios, GraphQL, NODE JS, Mongo DB, Express JS, JSON, XML, AWS, NPM, Visual Studio Code.

Sparkly Affiliate | ikeja, lagos

Front End Developer | 08/2021 - 01/2022

- Web design and development, application development using HTML, CSS, React, Bootstrap, Tailwind.
- Designed dynamic and multi-browser compatible pages using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, REACT and also developer responsive interface using Bootstrap, Tailwind and SASS, LESS for CSS.
- Created and deployed new features in order to sustain and amend existing applications under MVC pattern using Node.js,
- React js ,Bootstrap or Tailwind and Express.
- Developed the Frontend by using React, JavaScript, React router dom, Redux Toolkit by Package manager NPM.
- Developed cross-browser/platform HTML 5, CSS3, and JavaScript to match design specs for complex page layouts while adhering to code standards.
- Responsible for parsing JSON data to & from the server for presentation & storage purposes in the project .
- Environment: Html 5, CSS 3, LESS, SASS, JavaScript, ES6, React JS, Redux, NODE JS, Mongo DB, Express JS, JSON,XML, AWS.

Task Culture | ikeja, lagos

Front End Engineer | 04/2019 - 08/2021

- Web design and development, application development using HTML, CSS, React, Bootstrap, Tailwind.
- Designed dynamic and multi-browser compatible pages using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, REACT and also developer responsive interface using Bootstrap, Tailwind and SASS, LESS for CSS.
- Created and deployed new features in order to sustain and amend existing applications under MVC pattern using Node.js,React js ,Bootstrap or Tailwind and Express.

- Developed the Frontend by using React, JavaScript, React router dom, Redux Toolkit by Package manager NPM.
- Developed cross-browser/platform HTML 5, CSS3, and JavaScript to match design specs for complex page layouts while adhering to code standards.
- Responsible for parsing JSON data to & from the server for presentation & storage purposes in the project .

Environment: Html 5, CSS 3, LESS, SASS, JavaScript, ES6, React JS,Redux, NODE JS, Mongo DB, Express JS, JSON,XML, AWS.

Bouchard Agency | yaba, lagos Front End Web Developer/Designer | 06/2017 - 03/2019

- · Worked with an agile team of 12 members and provided end-to-end solutions for clients
- I had the responsibility to train 4 people the front-end basics and helped them develop further
- · Daily maintenance of code, debugging issues and solving clients' problems
- Gathered requirements and assembled team of web developers and UX designers to build out new ticketing system, generating a scalable e-commerce platform that served millions of users per day

Macroonz | ikeja, lagos Junior Front End Developer | 02/2016 - 06/2017

- Ensured end-to-end process of data extraction until reporting and noted efficiency of close to 25%.
- Developed my team-work skills by working in close collaboration with 6 other students.
- Developed prototypes, user interface design, and wireframes for the company website of a client, which included creating landing pages.
- Led the integration of a customer service chat functionality to answer user questions and schedule.
- consultations, resulting in a 15% increase in leads.
- Partnered with web developers and software developers to create a mobile application for insurance customers, which included supporting back-end development and UI design.

Skills

ReactJS, CSS, Web Development, JavaScript, Restful api, axios, Express.js, MongoDB, GraphQL, Node.js

Education

Anchorsoft | ikeja, lagos Python(Django)

Escae Universitie | Benin, cotonou BSC Human Resource Management

Github

https://github.com/FRVR-JAE